There it is again!
Wha-- Where is it coming from?
[BOTH gasp]
[NARRATOR] Setting camp at
the ruins of Utgard Castle
for the night,
the Scouts found themselves
overtaken by a Titan horde.
Their chances of survival low.
[CHRISTA]
Nanaba. Gelgar.
I'm sorry, Daddy!
I'll be a good girl
from now on, I promise!
[NARRATOR]
But when all seemed lost.
[YMIR]
Listen to me.
When you break it down,
this is really
just more of a hope.
Christa. Live a life
you can be proud of.
[CHRISTA]
Ymir! Wait!
[NARRATOR] One of their own
made a shocking transformation.
Yeah! Atta girl!
[YMIR TITAN]
Wanna live? Grab on tight.
[CONNY]
That's not good.
[Gasps]
[CONNY]
They're eating her!
[CHRISTA] No! I still
haven't told you my name!
I promised you!
[NARRATOR] The main force
of the Scout Regiment
swooped in and
engaged the enemy.
Die!
[NARRATOR] The Titan assault
fell before their blades.
[MIKASA yells]
[NARRATOR] However, standing
on the wreckage of battle,
Eren and the others
bore witness
to a heartbreaking confession.
[CHRISTA]
Ymir.
Just as promised.
My real name is Historia.
♪ Opening Song
That's it.
Bring it up slowly.
Steady the ropes, please.
[EREN]
What's the verdict?
How bad a shape is Ymir in?
[KEIJI] Well, she's missing
an arm and a leg.
And her insides are scrambled.
If she was normal,
she'd be a goner.
[EREN]
Normal, huh?
[REINER groans]
[EREN]
Here, grab my hand.
Thanks.
[CHRISTA] Please,
you've got to believe me!
I'm telling the truth!
Ymir could've run away
any time she wanted!
She chose to fight the
Titans to save our lives!
She had nothing to gain
putting herself
on the line like that.
Doesn't that speak volumes
about where her loyalties are?
She should have
told us before, yes.
She had no right to keep
her power a secret.
It's hard to look past how much
humankind might've gained
from knowing what she's been
keeping to her self, but...
I think... I think
she was just worried
about what people
might do to her.
Clearly her priorities
have changed now.
This isn't nearly as
complicated as it looks.
No one is closer
to Ymir than me,
and there's no question in my
mind whose side she's on!
Is that so?
Well, under
the circumstances
it certainly behooves us
to be friendly.
Her priorities aside,
I'll wager what she can
teach us about the enemy
is beyond measure. Probably.
Even so. You say this
isn't as complicated
as it looks, but from
where I'm standing
the world gets more
complicated by the hour.
[HANGE] Oh, uh--Historia Reiss
you said your name was?
I did. That's correct.
[HANGE] Isn't Reiss the name
of a noble family?
Yes, it is.
Huh.
Historia, nice to meet'cha.
Thank you.
[HANGE]
How's she doing?
Comatose but stable.
The bleeding's stopped,
though steam appears to be
coming out of her wounds.
Best course of action
is taking her back to Trost
where the poor girl can
get proper medical care.
She's in your hands.
Consider it done.
Right, then.
On with our mission.
Finding the hole
and patching it up.
[REINER exhales]
Son of bitch.
You okay over there, Reiner?
[REINER]
Not by a long shot.
Titan almost gnawed my arm off.
Pathetic. All I could think
was "this it how I go."
What else you s'posed
to think at time like that?
You're only human.
Don't you get it?
This was my second time!
Armin! Remember?
Huh?
[REINER]
Go on!
Tell him how Annie nearly
crushed me like an insect!
[ARMIN]
Yeah.
That's twice
I've nearly died now.
What are the chances
I'll survive a third time?
This is what it really means.
What it is to be soldier.
Your spirit breaks
and the body follows.
Eh. No good
whining about it now.
'Least not till we can
plug up the wall.
That's true. The two
of you have been driven
far enough away from
your hometown as it is.
--[REINER gasps]
--This is it.
This is where
we draw the line.
[BERTHOLDT] Truer words
were never spoken!
Home! Let's go!
We've been here long enough!
Compared to everything
else we've had
to go through,
the rest is easy!
You're right.
We don't have much further
to go before it's done!
[EREN]
What are guys talking about?
I needed that. Thanks.
Are you injured?
Nah, I'm okay,
but, Reiner's wounded.
And Ymir's sure
seen better days.
[SASHA] Who would've ever
pegged her for a Titan?
--Are they?
--[MIKASA] Sasha.
[HANGE]
We all on the same page?
We'll decide what to do
with Ymir later.
Oh, and Conny?
Chin up. I'll order a squad
to investigate your village.
For now, stay focused.
I want our energy on
the task at hand. Clear?
Crystal!
[HANGE]
It's troubling.
You would expect this area
to be teeming with Titans.
Hm?
[SASHA]
Hannes?
Is that the
Garrison advance squad?
Tell me they've
located the breach.
Wall's perfectly fine.
What?
[HANNES] Spent all night
trying to find out
where they're getting in.
But between Trost and Krolva
District, there's nothing.
No hole anywhere.
That's impossible!
We ran into a
search party from Krolva
and retraced our steps.
Not a single Titan
on the way here either.
[ARMIN] But we know for a fact
that there are Titans
on this side of Wall Rose.
Oh, C'mon.
How much have you
had to drink, seriously?
Why you little!
Hold on, wait a second.
What the hell are
you kids even doing here?
If there's no breach,
then I guess we
have to change tactics.
We head back
to Trost immediately.
You'd be smart
to keep your guard up.
We'll go on ahead of you.
How can there be
nothing wrong with the wall?
[ARMIN]
Excellent question.
Nothing like this
has happened in five years.
Why now all of a sudden?
[SASHA] Feels like everything's
spiraling out of control.
[REINER]
Eren.
We should talk.
You got a moment?
Sure, I guess.
[REINER] Five years ago,
we compromised Wall Maria
and launched
an attack on humanity.
Oh no. What if there's
a species of Titan
we haven't seen yet
that knows how to dig?
Ugh. That would
definitely make
their entry point hard to find.
[REINER] I'm the Armored Titan.
He's the Colossal.
[HANGE]
We can hypothesize later.
Our first concern is Ymir.
[MOBLIT] Titans being a close
second, even with the horses.
What are you talking about?
Why are you telling him?
Reiner, no!
--Stop!
--We were on a mission.
Our goal was to ensure
mankind's extinction.
But now,
there's no need for that.
Eren, if you want the
walls to remain standing,
it's simple. Just come
with Bertholdt and me.
Do you understand?
Understand? What the hell
is there to understand?
[REINER] Listen to me. I need
you to do exactly as I say.
[REINER] Look, I know this is
sudden, but we have to go.
Right now?
Where would you take me?
I can't tell you. Not yet.
Just think of it
as our hometown.
Okay? So what's it gonna be?
[Gasps]
[REINER]
Not a bad deal, right?
The chance to avert
a major crisis?
I'm not so sure.
You guys! Get a move on,
we're heading out!
[EREN] Damn it.
I didn't want to believe
what I was hearing yesterday.
[Horse neighs]
[HANGE]
Hmmm.
[EREN] Section Commander?
Something wrong?
Uh--Huh? Oh, uh,
well I was finally able
to get my hands on
the background report
I requested for Annie Leonhart.
Annie?
[HANGE] Yeah. Took longer
than I was hoping for.
The paper trail's a bit of
a catastrophe at the moment.
Bureaucracy, huh?
Anyway, according to this,
there were two other cadets
in the 104th who haled
from the same region.
I have their names.
One Reiner Braun
and Bertholdt Hoover.
[Gasps]
Not much survives
in the way of records,
and thanks to the chaos
five years ago,
what we have on them
is unreliable.
However, we do know
that during the long-range
scouting formation, their
unit was given false intel.
They were among those
intentionally misled into
thinking Eren
was in the right wing.
[Gasps]
Wait just a minute.
That's the section
Annie attacked.
[SASHA]
What? What does that mean?
Well, it's entirely
possible they told Annie
where they thought Eren was.
Huh? Why would they do that?
Where are you
going with this, Armin?
You can't just accuse--!
[HANGE]
I totally agree.
Coincidence doesn't
establish relationship.
Bearing that in mind,
I'm curious to know
how the three interacted
while training.
What can you tell me?
I knew Bertholdt and Reiner
were from the same region
as Annie, but I never
saw them act friendly.
Same with me.
You'd never catch 'em
shootin' the breeze.
And when they did talk
it was pretty curt.
Plus, it's not like Annie was
very social to begin with.
Yeah, at meals
she always seemed to prefer
eating by herself. I dunno.
Ah! I think I've got
something that struck me
as weird at the time.
I, uh...
heard she liked sweets!
I've got nothing.
Except maybe that--
[EREN]
Guys. What are we doing?
These are our comrades
we're talking about.
Yeah, sure. Bertholdt
never has a lot to say.
But Reiner's like everyone's
big brother, y'know?
You really think
he's capable of lying to us?
Eren does have a point.
Think about it.
Reiner fought the Female Titan
with everything he had.
Almost got himself squeezed to
a bloody pulp in the process.
--[Gaspss]
--What's the matter?
He burst free of her grip
at the last minute.
Afterwards, though,
Annie changed her course.
In fact, she ran straight
toward where you were.
I-- I mentioned
that you might be
rear of the center rank,
but there's no way
she could've heard me.
She wasn't in earshot
at the time.
You've gotta be kidding.
Do you recall if he seemed
unusually interested
in Eren's location?
So, where the hell
do you think he is?
[ARMIN]
Oh, no.
I only brought his position
up in the first place
because Reiner asked me where
I thought Eren might be.
Something else.
Once he broke free,
the Female Titan stood
there staring at her palm,
possibly transfixed
by something
he'd carved onto it
with his blades.
Maybe Reiner...
What is wrong
with you people?
The man's been with us
from the beginning!
--You don't just--
--[HANGE] Enough!
All of you. Listen up.
If we cross paths
with the pair in question,
don't give them any indication
of what we've discussed.
And under no
circumstances are you
to broach the topic of Annie
Leonhart in their company.
Before we can ascertain whether
they were co-conspirators,
we must find, lure,
and contain them underground.
That's the plan. Are we clear?
[SOLDIERS]
Yes, clear!
You're just tired.
That's it, right?
Help me out here, Betholdt.
Your nerves are shot.
You don't know
what you're saying.
[BERTHOLDT]
Uh. Yeah.
It's the battle fatigue talking!
It's okay. You're okay.
If you really were
the Armored Titan,
what's the endgame here?
We wouldn't be having this
conversation in the first place.
What'd you expect
me to do? Say yes?
Let myself be kidnaped just
'cause you asked politely?
[REINER gasps]
[REINER] Right.
Not thinking straight, am I?
Barely know
what I'm saying here.
Must've gone off the deep end.
C'mon, let's go.
[REINER]
That's the problem.
Heh.
I've been here too long
for my own good.
Three years of this madness,
surrounded by idiots.
We were kids. What'd we
know about anything?
Why did there have to be
people like this?
Why? Why did I
let myself devolve
into such a half-assed
piece of shit?
It's too late now.
Damned if I know
what's right anymore!
Who cares?
It is what it is.
No choice but
to face what I've done.
[BOTH gasp]
As a warrior.
No road left but the one
that leads to the end!
Reiner! Right now?
Here? We're doing this?
Yes. Right here, right now!
We settle this
once and for all!
--[MIKASA grunts]
--[REINER groans]
--[BERTHOLDT groans]
[Groans]
Eren! Get out of here!
[REINER]
Bertholdt!
Eren! Run away!
[SASHA yells]
[Growls]
[Gasps]
Ymir!
No!
[REINER] I'm going
to return to the home
that was taken from me.
I will do it.
No matter what.
[EREN]
Bertholdt. Reiner.
Damn you! You traitors!
[EREN TITAN yells]
♪ Closing Song ♪